Vincent Vo

Systems Administrator | Identity & Access Management | Automation & Security | ITSM linkedin.com/in/vovincent12 | vincenttyo.github.jo

Professional Summary

Efficiency-driven IT Systems Administrator specializing in Identity & Access Management and automation, enhancing user lifecycle management, and SaaS administration through Okta, Google Workspace, Workato, and APIs. Expertise in enforcing Zero Trust Policies, Role-Based Access Controls (RBAC), and Privileged Access Management (PAM) to enhance security posture. Proven success in implementing foundational ITSM programs, endpoint security (Kandji MDM, SentinelOne EDR), and SaaS integrations-enhancing corporate security, business, and user efficiency.

Core Competencies & Key Skills

- Identity & Access Management (IAM) & PAM: RBAC, Zero Trust, Adaptive MFA, SSO (SAML/OAuth)
- Automation & Scripting: Workato, BetterCloud, Python, Bash, REST APIs
- Administration & Security: Okta, Google Workspace, Microsoft 365, Kandji (MDM), SentinelOne (EDR)
- Lifecycle & ITSM: Provisioning, Onboarding/Offboarding, ServiceNow, Jira, Confluence
- Security Operations: Access Reviews, Adaptive MFA, Network Segmentation, SSO Implementation
- Integration & Secrets Management: API Integrations, 1Password

Experience

IT Systems Administrator | Measurabl, San Diego, CA

May 2022 - Present

- Automated IAM workflows, reducing provisional errors by 67% through integrating SaaS
 applications into Okta using SAML, OIDC, OAuth and SCIM, enabling SSO, automated provisioning and
 centralized authentication.
- Drove enforcement of RBAC, Device Trust, PAM policies reducing access requests by 50%, enhancing Zero Trust security, least privileged access, and conditional access for 200+ users.
- Optimized core systems (Okta, Google Workspace, Kandji, Slack) increasing administrative
 efficiency by 25% through feature adoption and integrating systems using Workato (IPaaS), REST APIs,
 and scripts.
- Developed and implemented ITSM programs increasing operational efficiency by 75%, by
 maximizing current SaaS tool usage and replacing an MSP vendor, creating an internal Service Desk,
 enhancing service delivery, user support, and partnering with HR and business teams to align IT services
 with business needs.
- Obtained SOC2 Type 2 certification by monitoring Drata, collecting provisioned access evidence, auditing user permissions and alerts in Okta, Google Workspace, SentinelOne, and reviewing security policies.

Senior Service Desk Analyst | Realty Income, San Diego, CA

July 2020 - May 2022

Promoted to Senior Service Desk Analyst in December 2021 initially hired as a Service Desk Analyst. Taking on advanced responsibilities. Leading the Service Desk Team and development of ITIL and Security practices.

- **Reduced unauthorized access by 15%** by enforcing least privileged access using Active Directory, Okta, and group policies, automating user provisioning, improving security and compliance.
- **Increased system uptime and user productivity** by administering Microsoft 365, Active Directory, Okta, and group policies, optimizing SaaS integrations and access management.

- Led a team of 5 improving ticket resolution by 25%, improving IT service delivery for end users.
- **Improved SOX audit compliance** by capturing evidence and audit logging, reducing audit friction and ensuring adherence to SOX controls.
- Managed PDQ Deploy for patch management for 200+ endpoints, automating security updates and maintaining system compliance.

Client Services Engineer | CARET (fka AbacusNext), San Diego, CA December 2018 - July 2020

- **Enhanced user experience for 300+ clients** by managing VMware Horizon virtual machines using Active Directory, group policies, patch management, and solving technical issues related to their used applications.
- Improved the efficiency of virtual machines for business client users by automating computer
 maintenance tasks with BAT scripts for disk drive cleaning, application management, and patch file
 removal.
- **Ensured satisfactory client issue resolution and optimized windows server performance** by collaborating with cloud engineers, providing exceptional service delivery.

Certifications

- **BetterCloud Administrator** | BetterCloud 2023
- ITIL 4 Strategist: Direct, Plan, and Improve | PeopleCert 2021
- ITIL 4 Foundation | PeopleCert 2021
- Google IT Support Professional | Coursera 2019

Education

Bachelor's in Interdisciplinary Studies (Kinesiology, Psychology, Sociology) | San Diego State University